<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Anthony Caravaggi</title>
    <link>https://arcaravaggi.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://arcaravaggi.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:37:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://arcaravaggi.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Anthony</title>
      <link>https://arcaravaggi.github.io/post/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:37:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arcaravaggi.github.io/post/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up in the South Wales valleys and I loved nature as a kid. That&amp;rsquo;s shocking information, I know, particularly coming from a biologist, but I offer no apologies; it is what it is. I was a pretty good kid, too, by all accounts, and I had an insatiable appetite for all things related to the natural world. I remember, of course, the Attenborough documentaries, but also being absolutely hooked on Disney&amp;rsquo;s White Wilderness, which I had on VHS (go and ask your parents). Unsurprisingly, I knew that I wanted to work with animals when I grew up,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or, even better, become a palaeontologist. Because dinosaurs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it went that I grew up, discovered sci-fi, Lego, rugby, cartoons and, slowly, the natural world and I drifted apart. Eventually, the impacts of a careers tutor who said that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford for me to go to University and the after-effects of an abusive father resulted in an enrolment in art college where I studyied 2D animation. After that, I worked in IT for my local council while doing acting classes and improvisational comedy of an evening. After 3 years of phone calls with word processing operators who couldn&amp;rsquo;t use a word processor, I decided it was time to follow my dream and become a wandering minstrel. That didn&amp;rsquo;t work out, so I settled for heading to University to study conservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bangor University in North Wales were good enough to offer me a place on a BSc course, despite it being nearly a decade since I&amp;rsquo;d last studied science or math(s; choose your variant). I&amp;rsquo;d gone into my undergrad hoping for a 2:2 and to get  work in practical conservation on a local reserve. Instead, I received a first class degree and realised that research is kind of cool and resolved to do more of that, if I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then began the first of the Barren Years. Terrible letters were sent as PhDs were sought; all were rejected without an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twelve months later I enrolled on a Master&amp;rsquo;s-by-Research (MRes) course at the University of Leeds, reasoning that the two research projects I would undertake would stand me in good stead for a future PhD. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I was less enthusiastic about that course. The research (bird ecology and ant genetics) was awesome, but the modules repeated much of my undergrad material. Nevertheless, regardless and, indeed, anyway, I emerged with a postgrad degree and embarked upon the second Barren Year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d learned a lot during my Master&amp;rsquo;s studies, and my cover letters improved dramatically. As a result, my PhD applications were increasingly successful. Six months later, I received a couple of offers and, another six months down the line, I was in Belfast. The PhD was hard(!); I had to up my game in all aspects. My peers were largely nice people but I had little in common with them and struggled with social events. My personal life was a total mess, too - my seven-year relationship collapsed and for much of the second and part of the third year, I lurched from crisis to crisis. I was a gnat&amp;rsquo;s breath from quitting at one point and impostor syndrome was (and remains) an almost constant companion. Luckily, I had an excellent supervisor and doing the PhD remains one of the most rewarding experiences of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three and a half years later, I graduated. In contrast to others in the office, I found the whole graduation process underwhelming. You spend months writing the thesis, there&amp;rsquo;s the wait for the viva, then the corrections, then the eventual graduation some months later. But still, the little kid who wanted to work with animals was ecstatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then began the third Barren Year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started applying for postdocs around 3 months out from the end of my PhD. Over the next 18 months I had over 20 interviews, getting close a total of 14 times. I kept working on papers and other projects in the meantime, but I was slowly being worn down. The only bright spot of this time was meeting my partner - now wife! - Kim, who is one of the most ridiculous people I have ever met. I mean that in a truly loving way. I finally received an offer of a position from University College Cork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The postdoc went very well, indeed. I worked with an excellent team and made some good friends. I knew that we were almost certainly going to have to move again and I was looking for something more permanent, as Kim was pregnant and neither of us were keen on the uncertainty that&amp;rsquo;s inherent in chasing postdoc positions. Towards the end of my contract, a couple of friends (who are a couple) let me know about a lecturer position that had opened up at the University of South Wales. The job was, amazingly enough, in the building that used to be the art college I attended. It seemed a perfect fit, came at just the right time, and management were (and are) extremely supportive of early career researchers who were looking for their first academic position. It was remarkably fortunate timing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now about a year and a half into my lectureship and it seems utterly bizarre to think that I am a professional scientist. My mother &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; says that she can&amp;rsquo;t believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be a lesson here, right? I&amp;rsquo;ve left out a lot of information - the personal demons, the sacrifices, the self-funding much of my undergrad and Master&amp;rsquo;s from savings and backup jobs, the many, many people who supported and helped me - and yes, there are plenty of things I could say as words of advice. But that&amp;rsquo;s not the point of this post. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure what the point of this post is, to be honest, except to say that this is where one particular scientist, where I, came from. &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original version of this post was 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://errantscience.com/blog/2017/07/03/a-brief-history-of-an-early-career-researcher/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;featured on the Errant Science blog&lt;/a&gt;
. That was 3 years ago. This version has been edited and updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up is a myth, and don&amp;rsquo;t let anyone tell you otherwise. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
